Bloom Southwest Jewish Archives photograph collection, 1850-1995
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series I: Arizona
  - Lesinsky. (Box 3)
    View of the San Francisco River - Clifton.
    Clifton street scene.
    Group photo (ca.1880-1885): Rose Hood; Bernard Weisl; Frances Weisl; Anna Weisl; Bertha Lesinsky; Mathias Recht; Emma Recht; Sigmund Weisl;Charles Lesinsky.
    Group photo in front of the Clifton Hotel: Sam Abraham; Jake Abraham.
    Freight wagons carrying hay and water to the copper mines,Arizona (1900s).
    Narrow gauge train between Clifton and Metcalf.
    Lesinsky Railroad from Clifton mines.
  - Levin, Alexander. (Box 3)
    Alexander Levin.
    Portrait of Alex Levin and wife Xenohia Molina de Levin.
  - Levy, D. (Box 3)
    D. Levy and Co. - General Merchandise and Palace Saloon(1903).
    Fair Store (Bisbee; 1995).
  - Levy, Leon: Levy holding a football. (Box 3)
  - Lipschultz, Menachem: Portrait at about 40 years of age(ca.1935). (Box 3)
  - Lisitzky family. (Box 3)
    Group photo: Navajo County Fair, Holbrook (1964).
    Max Lisitzky and his wife Mollie Lisitzky on their golden anniversary standing behind a cake.
  - Maimonidean Society (University of Arizona): Group photo(1941): Edmund Shulman; Eleanor Birdman; Alsie Raffman; Ruth Cohen; Ted Luri; Abe Chanin; Art Goldstaub. (Box 3)
  - Mansfeld family. (Box 3)
    Eva Goldschmitt Mansfeld.
    Jacob Samuel Mansfeld.
    Jacob Samuel Mansfeld and his family.
  - Marshall, Jonathan and Maxine: Portrait. (Box 3)
  - Miller, George: Portrait (Box 3)
  - Miller, Joseph and Ruth. (Box 3)
    At Bloom Southwest Jewish Archives.
    Ruth Ruiz Reed at Bloom Southwest Jewish Archives.
    Amulet of the Ten Commandments worn by Ruth Miller.
  - Mining and railroads. (Box 3)
    Group of men standing in front of the "Fashion Saloon."
    Horse and cart on a mountain side.
    Shannon Copper Company's reduction plant.
    Narrow gauge train.
    San Francisco River flooding.
    Mules freighting silver from Silver King Mine to the mill at Pinal City, AHS.
  - Moreno, Charles. (Box 3)
    Portrait: first kosher butcher in Tucson - a Mexican American non-Jew.
    NEGATIVE.
  - Murillo, Lupita: Lupita Murillo and godchild at the Bloom Southwest Jewish Archives. (Box 3)
  - Newman, Jack B.: Newman and E.B. Kellner(1880s). (Box 3)
  - Owls Club (Tucson): Owls Club building, 1990 (the Owls Club was a small and exclusive group of bachelors who enlivened Tucson from 1886-1912). (Box 3)
  - Perlman, Nathan David. (Box 3)
    Perlman holding his ceramic art works.
    Sculpture, entitled "Immortality," shows a kneeling women and an infant.
    With his sculpture of a reclining figure.
    Perlman with sculpture of three figures together.
    Perlman with sculpture of a seated woman and a child.
    Sculpture entitled "The Wanderers;" two figures are shown on a bed.
    Sculptures of the head of a woman.
    Sculpture entitled "Discovery."
    Sculpture entitled "Praying girl."
  - Pioneer Women of Arizona Doll Collection. (Box 3)
    Collection of dolls of pioneer Jewish women.
    Doll of Jennie Migel Drachman.
    Doll of Bettina Donau Steinfeld.
    Doll of Julia Frank Zeckendorf.
    Doll of Julia Kaufman Strauss.
    Doll of Terese Marx-Ferrin.
    Doll of Josephine Marcus Earp.
    Doll of Clara Ferrin Bloom.
    Doll of Dora Loon Capin.
    Doll of Anna Freudenthal Solomon.
    Doll of Rosa Katzenstein Drachman.
    Dolls: Anna Freudenthal Solomon; Terese Marx Ferrin; Rosa K. Drachman.
    Dolls: Julia Kaufman Strauss; Julia Frank Zeckendorf; Dora Loon Capin.
    Dolls: Josephine Marcus Earp; Bettina Donau Steinfeld.
  - Prescott buildings. (Box 3)
    Prescott after 1900 fire.
    Hampton Funeral Home.
    Various homes.
    Stained glass window.
    Contact sheet and NEGATIVES sheet.
  - Rothman, Ed: Ed Rothman (ca.1903). (Box 3)
  - San Xavier del Bac Mission. (Box 3)
    A. Steinfeld scratched his name on stairwell (1890).
    "Aaron Zeckendorf" (1871) etched on the wall.
    Graffiti, names of Alexander Levin, Zenona Levin on wall.
    Name of Goldman.
    Name of Harry S. Goldman etched into the stairwell.
    Contact sheets and negatives.
  - Schuster Store (Holbrook). (Box 3)
    A & B Schuster Company store (ca.1920s).
    A & B Schuster Company store (ca.1929).
    Schuster store (1965-66).
    Holbrook before the fire (ca. 1888).
    Interior of the Holbrook store (1890s).
    A & B Schuster general merchandise store (ca. 1884).
  - Shiff family. (Box 3)
    Group photos: Mr. and Mrs. Shiff; their son Howard.
    Mr. and Mrs. Shiff.
    Howard Shiff in a football uniform.
    Costume party; Eva Shiff (April 1949).
  - Shulman, Alsie Raffman: Portrait of faculty member at University of Arizona (ca. 1920s). (Box 3)
  - Silver Bell Road objects: Objects found on Tucson's Silver Bell Road (September 13, 1924) by hiker Charles Manier. The relics are made upof silver and tin with curious inscriptions, crosses and Christian symbols, Moslem crescents, candelabra, and Latin phrases. (Box 3)
  - Sisterhood of Tucson: Group photo (ca.1892). (Box 3)
  - Solomon business. (Box 3)
    Blanche and Anna Solomon in a horse and carriage (ca. 1902).
    Solomons' store.
    Group photo: George H. Kelly; Dan Ming; John Fitzgerald; Cal Leitch; Judge Rouse; Gov. Franklin; I.E. Solomon (1897).
    Solomon's Copperhill store (1909). Harry Solomon is third from the left.
    The Solomon store.
    Gila Valley Bank - first office in Solomon Commercial Store.
    Sign which reads "I.E.Solomon dealer in general merchandise."
    Advertisement for I. E. Solomon's store.
    Group photo: inside of Solomon Commercial Store.
    Group photo: inside of Solomon's store.
    Dedication ceremony of the Highway 20 marker for Solomonville(November 23, 1957).
    Solomon Hotel (1906).
    Montezuma Flour Mill in Solomonville.
    Norma Clark in front of post office (ca. 1906).
    View of Solomonville.
    Exterior of the Solomon Commercial Company (ca. 1912).
    Invitation to the execution of Augustin Chacol on Nov. 12, 1902.
    Stock certificate: Gila Valley Bank to I.E. Solomon (1900).
    Registered IE cattle brand of Solomon (October 13, 1885).
    Interior of the Commercial Co farm equipment store (1913); H. Solomon; F. Blake; G. Robbins(?).
    Wagon freight between Clifton and Solomonville.
    The Solomon/Weinberger wedding (ca. June 1907).
  - Solomon family. (Box 3)
    Group photo: Frieda Freudenthal Mashkin; Mollie Freudenthal;Louis Freudenthal; Anna Solomon; Nattie Ferrin Solomon.
    Lillie and Blanche Solomon (ca. 1901).
    Mr. and Mrs. I.E. Solomon (Los Angeles)on their Golden Wedding Anniversary (1921).
    Rosalie Freudenthal (mother of Anna Solomon).
    Louis Freudenthal (father of Anna Solomon).
    I.E. Solomon (1894).
    Group photo: Wolf Freudenthal; Frieda Freudenthal; Phoebus Freudenthal; Morris Freudenthal; Anna Freudenthal Solomon and Isadore Elkan Solomon (1888).
    Group photo - wedding of Lillie Solomon and Max Lantin: Harry Solomon; Rose Solomon Goldberg; David Goldberg; Lillie Solomon; Max Lantin; Blanche Solomon; Eva Solomon Wetzler; Harold Goldberg; Isadore Solomon holding a photograph of Julius Wetzler; Ru th Goldberg; Anna Solomon; Sidney Wetzler; Charles Solomon (August 14, 1904).
    Group photograph (unidentified).
    The Solomonville baseball team (ca. 1898): John Nash; Jake Sellers; Charles Solomon; I.E. Solomon; patron; Luther Green; Charles Thompson; W.B. Kelly; Andy Alexander; John Alexander.
    Anna Solomon (1918).
    Group photo: Charles F. Solomon on roof with camera.
    Charles F. Solomon at age 20 (1893).
    Group photo - "Carnival Queen and her Attendants": Lillie Solomon (Solomonville); Maude Marsh (Prescott); Kate Sherman (Kingsman); Miss Kingman (Globe); Miss Laura Peak (Yuma); Lena Pordy (Phoenix); Agnes Todd (Flagstaff); Hazel Goldberg (Phoenix); Ru th Jossop (Phoenix).
    Philip and Elizabeth with mother, Lillie Lantin (1918).
  - Spielberg, Steven. (Box 3)
  - Spitalny family. (Box 3)
    Max Spitalny (1925).
    Sam Spitalny holding a violin at his Bar Mitzvah (1913).
    Sam Spitalny and a cow (1945).
    Sam Sptalny on a horse (1928).
    Betty Spitalny with the grand champion bull (1934).
    Larry Spitalny with his prize winning bull (1946).
    Feed for Sam's cattle (1949).
  - Stein/Miller families. (Box 3)
    Henry Stein (ca. 1900).
    House where Walter Stein was born (Tucson; ca. 1910).
    Ray, AZ, facing toward Sonora (ca. 1920).
    Hettie Schoenthal Stein at picnic in Ray, Arizona (ca. 1920).
    Mrs. Jacob Miller (Gertrude Schoenthal) and children (ca. 1915).
    Group photo: Juliet M. Ferria and others in Grandpa Franklin's Ford (ca. 1919).
    Three Miller brothers and families (Sal, Jake, and Al; ca.1920).
    Juliet Miller at age 10 years and seven months (1910).
    Advertisement which reads "Jacob Miller representing Julius Goldbaum" (ca. 1899).
    Ruth Stein and Juliet Miller.
  - Steinfeld family. (Box 3)
    Steinfeld's store (Tucson).
    Grocery department of Albert Steinfeld Store (1880s).
    Photo of interior of Steinfeld Department Store (1890s).
    Steinfeld mansion (1990).
    Albert Steinfeld (ca.1882).
    Mrs. Albert Steinfeld (ca.1880).
  - Stone Avenue Temple (Tucson, Arizona): Re-dedication ceremony of the Stone Avenue Temple (November 6, 1994). (Box 3)
  - Strauss, Julia: Photograph of Julia Kaufman Strauss (wife of Charles M. Strauss; ca.1880s). (Box 4)
  - Temple Beth Shalom (Green Valley, Arizona). (Box 4)
    Temple Beth Shalom (February 22, 1995) - dedication ceremony.
    Helen Chazonaf (wife of Zev Chazonaf) at the dedication of Temple Beth Shalom.
    Pincus Glick reciting prayers in Hebrew while Augusta Feinstein translates, at dedication of Temple.
    Roslyn Sirata speaking on "Coming of Age" at the dedication of Temple.
    David Sirata singing; Ann Schaffer at piano.
    Rev. Joe Carroll, at the dedication of Temple.
    David Sirata speaking at the dedication.
    Zev William Chazanof at the dedication.
    Lester Somon at the dedication.
    Torah being presented at the dedication.
    Dr. Lillian Solomon reciting the blessing over the candles.
    Henry Brodsky holding the Torah in front of the ark at the dedication.
    Michael Sirata at the dedication.
    David Sirata and his son Michael singing a duet at the dedication.
    Rev. Tim Holt at the dedication.
    Henry Feinstein at the dedication.
    Herbert Morgan and his wife Mary Ann leading the procession to carry the Torah to the ark.
    Unidentified individuals at ark; Morris (Sonny) Gucerst (the builder of the ark) stands to the right.
    Cappy Gallant blessing the bread.
    Cappy Gallant in front of the ark handing bread to Herbert Morgan.
    Eternal Light over the ark.
  - Temple Emanu-El (Tucson, Arizona). (Box 4)
    Original Temple Emanu-El; plaque at the Temple site (1988).
    Original Temple Emanu-El.
    Plaque at site.
    Members of the Young Singers; one of the Tums quartet, which included Sam Zavalo(?); Murray Fruchtman; Stanley Nivens; Ed Bloom (ca.1946).
  - Temple Solel (Paradise Valley, Arizona). (Box 4)
    Exterior view.
    Stained glass window on the exterior of the Temple.
    View of the bimah (prayer stage) in the sanctuary.
    Door leading to the Al and Fran Sachs Family Sanctuary inside of the Temple.
    Ark in the sanctuary.
    "Tree of Life."
    Memorial plaques which contain the names of "The Builders."
    Sanctuary.
    A wall-hanging in the sanctuary.
    Art work in the Temple.
    Stained glass window, from the inside.
    Artwork in the sanctuary.
  - Tombstone, Arizona cemetery. (Box 4)
    Plaque dedicated to Jewish pioneers and their Indian friends by Jewish Friendship Club (1984).
    Headstone.
  - Tucson, AZ. (Box 4)
    Pennington Street - Park Brewery (ca. 1881).
    View of Tucson Plaza.
    View of Meyer Street.
  - Tucson historic Torah flight: Ceremony involving the sending of a Torah to Israel (l-r): Robert Imberman; Mrs. & Mr. Morris Grossman; Dr. Marcus Breger; Stan Phillips (March 25, 1958). (Box 4)
  - Tucson Jewish Community Council. (Box 4)
  - Tucson Jewish organizations. (Box 4)
    Group portrait: five men; four women; Abe Chanin; David Bloom; Leona Bloom.
    Group photograph of 3 men reading a paper.
    Group photograph: David N. Ginsburg; Marvin H. Volk; Ambassador James Roosevelt; Stanley A. Katcher; four men are gathered around a newspaper called "The Mitzvah" (1957).
    Five men; Marvin Volk is standing to the far right.
    Five men and five women. Standing from left to right: Paul Baker; Lex Sears; David Leonard; Dan Karsch. Seated from left to right: Betty Anne Krause; Alice Baker; Judith Sears; Judy Leonard; Carol Karsch.
    Group photograph: Liz Cohen; Benjamin N. Brook; Morris Cohen.
    Group photograph: Sylvia Fiese; Harry Fiese; Mrs. Aaron Stiglitz; Leonard Scheff (1970s).
    Group photograph: M.H. Bolk; Morris K. Udall; Benjamin N. Brook; Yale Stuart (1960s).
    Group photograph: Benjamin N. Brook; Mary Jefferies; Harry Goden; Ethel Gorodess; Fred Rosen - at evening fund raising (1960s).
    Group photograph: Gov. Howard Pyle; Benjamin N. Brook; David Kramer (1950s).
    Group photograph: Rabbi Breger; George Jessel; B.N. Brook; M.Schwerin; H. Kaufman (1950).
  - Udall family. (Box 4)
    David K. Udall and his first residence at St. Johns (ca.1880).
    Udall and his basketball teammates (ca. 1940s).
  - United Jewish Appeal. (Box 4)
    Group photograph: Ben Bemer; Sadie Danciger; Lillian Goldwyn; Inga Kaufman; Gertrude Kaliher (1950s).
    Presentation of check to United Jewish Appeal by Carol Stern and Alvin D. Stern (1970s).
  - University of Arizona. (Box 4)
    A meeting of students, Rabbi Bilgray, and others at home of Naomi Dumes (1940s).
    Old Main (1897-98).
  - Weizenbaum, Rabbi Joseph: Rabbi Weizenbaum and his wife. (Box 4)
  - Zeckendorf family. (Box 4)
    Zeckendorf and Company freight wagon.
    L. Zeckendorf store (at corner of Main and Pennington, Tucson, Arizona).
    Congress and Main St., looking north toward Zeckendorf and Stash Store (ca.1874).
    Directory (1881). W.M. Zeckendorf noted as merchant, and sole agent for Bain Wagon.
    L. Zeckendorf building (ca. 1882).
    Zeckendorf Store decorated for the General Miles celebration(1887).
    Parade in honor of Gen. Nelson A. Miles.
    Employees and bystanders in front of store (1896). Three photos; includes: Harry A. and Mose Drachman; Albert Steinfeld; Louis Zeckendorf.
    Portrait: Johanna Zilenfeld Zeckendorf; her mother; daughter Julia; granddaughter, Frieda Steinfeld in Hanover, Germany (ca. 1864).
    William Zeckendorf and family at picnic (ca.1888).
    Zeckendorf family.
    Louis Zeckendorf (ca.1854).
    Louis Zeckendorf, with cane (ca. 1931).
    William Zeckendorf (ca. 1875)
    Julia Zeckendorf (ca.1875).
    Mrs. William Zeckendorf (nee Julia Frank; ca. 1880s).
    Mrs. William Zeckendorf (ca. 1880s).
    Mrs. William Zeckendorf (1880s).
    William Zeckendorf II and Harold Steinfeld.
    Home of William Zeckendorf (1890).
- Series II: New Mexico.
  - Amberg, Jacob: Jacob Amberg. (Box 4)
  - Atencio, D. Tomas: Dr. Tomas Atencio. (Box 4)
  - Bibo family. (Box 4)
    Solomon Bibo (governor of Acoma) and his officers (1885); l-r: Jose Miguel Chirco; Pedro Sanchez (Indian Agent); Hashti Martin de Valle; Jose Berendo, principal; Santiago Orilla; Santiago Conipo Linazeteah; Lorenzo Pancho; Lorenzo Lino; Lorenzo Schau wa Kury; Toribio Mateai; Jose Ant Aujune; Napoleon Paricho; Andres Oritz (interpreter); Secretary of Indian Agent; Solomon Bibo, Governor of Acoma; Hashti in Acoma Language means "Old Man"(photo appears to be taken in Grants, N.M., presumably in 1885). Two story section house of Santa Fe Railroad in distance.
    Seven men standing in front of a house (Grants, N.M.?; ca.1885).
    Mr. and Mrs. Nathan Bibo, seated; Mr. and Mrs. Joseph Bibo, standing.
    Simon Bibo.
    Simon Bibo's store at Laguna, N.M. (ca. 1900).
    Joseph Bibo (bowtie) and his wife in front of his store in Bernalillo, N.M.; boy with dog; James Bibo (their oldest son) next to him; Milton Bibo(second son); girl in wagon; Reina Bibo (Stolaroff) (their daughter).
    The Bibo family tree.
    Interior view of a store and five unidentified men.
    Headstones of Isak Bibo and his wife (Grants N.M.; ca. 1920s).
    Linita Bibo Weiss and husband, Gus Weiss in front of Cubero Store, N.M. (ca. 1890s).
    Petition not to revoke Solomon Bibo's traders’ license.
    Bibo family, standing, l-r: Rica Bierman; Betty Bibo; Lena Bibo/Weiss; Willie Bierman; Flora Bibo; Clara Bibo; unknown person; Irma Bibo; Adolph Bierman; unknown person; seated, l-r: unknown person; Nathan Bibo; Carl Seligman; Lucille Seligman; Joseph Bibo.
    Joseph Bibo.
    NEGATIVES and contact sheet.
  - Bibo, NM. (Box 4)
  - B'nai B'rith cemetery records (Albuquerque). (Box 4)
  - B'nai Israel Congregation (Albuquerque). (Box 4)
  - Cemeteries and monuments (Jewish). (Box 4)
  - Clever, Charles. (Box 4)
    Document of appointment as Marshal, Territory of New Mexico (1858); NEGATIVE.
    Document about pay to Anglo men in the militia (1861, 1862).
    Group photo; l-r: General Daniel H. Rucker; Col. Kit Carson; Brig. Gen. James H. Carleton; standing, l-r: Lt. Col. E.H. Bergmann; Charles P.Clever; Col. Nelson H. Davis; Maj. Herbert M. Enos; Surgeon Basil K. Norris; Col. J.C. McFerren.
    Augustine de Marie and C.P. Clever.
  - Danoff family (NOTE: many of these photos were copied from an album). (Box 4)
    Five different coins owned by Hyman Danoff.
    Certificate appointing Sam Danoff as Postmaster General in Danoffville.
    Hyman Danoff's bar mitzvah momentos.
    Hyman Danoff (1988).
    Signs for "Rodeo Grounds, 1 [mile]" and "Danoff, 11 [miles]."
    Sam Danoff; with gray hair and glasses.
    Sam Danoff as a young man
    Mrs. Samuel Danoff.
    Three 5x7 portraits of Bertha Danoff.
    Young Bertha Danoff sitting in a chair.
    Ludwig Heyman family.
    Documents photographed relating to the Danoff/Heyman families of Albuquerque, Gallup and Danoffville.
    Danoff family photos.
    Bertha Heyman-Danoff.
  - Duran, Dennis. (Box 4)
    Portrait of Dennis Duran taken at the International Conference on Inquisition/Hidden Jews (the University of Arizona; January 27, 1991).
    One NEGATIVE (Dennis Duran).
  - Fischbein family. (Box 4)
    Portraits of Louis Fischbein (?).
    Photo taken in Cd. Chihuahua of Kate F. Taylor, Louis Fischbein, Johanna Fischbein, Max Fischbein, and Anita Fischbein Ehrsam.
    Johanna, Louis, and Max Fischbein on a hunting trip (1904; Parral, Mexico).
  - Floersheim family. (Box 4)
    Photographs of the Floersheims' ranch houses (including ice house, chicken house, cook house, bunk house, Donald's home, sheds for sheep, dipping vats, corral, water source, etc.).
    Correspondence between the Floersheim Mercantile Co. and Oliver P. Easterwood. Letters are dated January 8, 1908 and November 23, 1908.
    Correspondence between Carl Floersheim and Dr. Floyd Fierman. Letter is dated July 14, 1953.
    Correspondence between Floersheim Mercantile Co. and S.A. Mestas. Letter is dated November 1908.
    The cover of the Floersheim day book which reads "Floersheim Day Book 1918".
    Page from the Floersheim day book (1918).
    Maps of New Mexico.
    Aerial photo of headquarters, showing Lake Rhoecing(?).
    Two photos of Solomon Floersheim and his son Milton (with a skull cap on his head; early 1900s).
    Milton and Ben Floersheim as little boys (taken at Springer, NM; ca. 1895). Another photo of Ben and Milton Floersheim taken while cadets at Blees Military Academy in Macon, MO.
    1941 brand book of the State of New Mexico showing all the brands registered for cattle, horses, mules and asses (1941).
    Four copies of the Floersheims' brands for cattle and sheep.
    Two photos of Milton Floersheim, Sr. (taken shortly before his death; 1957).
    Photo of (l-r):Elizabeth Weiskoff Bibo (Mrs. Emil Bibo); Irma Bibo Floersheim; Ben Floersheim; Eleanor Floersheim Seligman; Randy Seligman;Donald Floersheim (1952).
    Milton, Ben, and Carl Floersheim (photo taken by Don Floersheim in his living room at Jaritas Ranch; ca. 1950).
    Irma Belle Bibo Floersheim and Ben Floersheim.
    Group photo of Milton and his wife, Fanny Abenheimer Floersheim; Ben and wife; Irma Bibo Floersheim; Carl and wife; Cora Wise Floersheim (ca. 1950).
    Marriage contract (ketubah) uniting S. Floersheim and Emma Blumenthal (December 25, 1884 New Mexico).
    Ben Floersheim's swaddling cloth as transformed into Torah binder (wimpel).
  - Freudenthal family. (Box 4)
    First advertisement for the Silver City Bank as it appeared in the Silver City Enterprise (March 7, 1884).
    Group photo in front of the Hotel Don Bernardo(ca. 1904).
  - Freudenthal, Samuel: Samuel Freudenthal. (Box 4)
  - Gallup, NM: Buildings once owned by Jewish merchants. (Box 4)
  - Goodman, Jacob: United States of America Certificate of Citizenship issued to Jacob Goodman (Las Cruces, NM; April 4,1904). (Box 4)
  - Gusdorf store (Taos, NM). (Box 5)
    Photo of south side of plaza in Taos; Columbian Hotel and Taos Bar on the left, Gusdorf store is at the end of the street (ca. 1917).
    Plaza in Taos; general store on left; courthouse?(ca.1917).
  - Hernandez, Dr. Frances: Dr. Frances Hernandez delivering a speech at the University of Arizona International Conference on the Inquisition/Hidden Jews in the Americas and the Southwest (January 27, 1991). (Box 5)
  - Hordes, Dr. Stanley M.: Dr. Stanley M. Hordes delivering a speech at the University of Arizona International Conference on the Inquisition/Hidden Jews in the Americas and the Southwest (January 27, 1991). (Box 5)
  - Ilfeld family. (Box 5)
    Page from a subscription book with list of stockholders of the Santa Fe Hotel and Building Company (1880, 1881).
    Ludwig Ilfeld on a horse (ca.1894).
    New York Governor Teddy Roosevelt on horse named Maude owned by Ludwig Ilfeld; Rough Riders reunion (June 21, 1899; Las Vegas, New Mexico).
    Fred Ilfeld at age seven with father and national guard officers (Columbus, NM; 1914).
    Young Ludwig W. Ilfeld in a western movie outfit.
    Major Ilfeld in uniform (Columbus, NM; ca. 1914).
    Ilfeld building at Las Vegas, New Mexico.
    Ludwig William Ilfeld in fire chief's uniform.
    Theodore Roosevelt on his horse at the Rough Riders parade (Las Vegas, NM; ca.1899s).
    Reunion of Rough Riders (Las Vegas, NM).
    Reunion of Rough Riders; includes Theodore Roosevelt (Las Vegas, NM).
    Officers Ludwig Ilfeld and unidentified others (ca. 1914; Columbus, NM).
    Col. Ludwig Ilfeld leading Las Vegas, New Mexico national guard unit at San Miguel Las Vegas courthouse to board train for Columbus, New Mexico (to chase Pancho Villa?; ca. 1914).
    Ilfeld family (standing, l-r): Luis Ilfeld; Johanna Ilfeld Judell; Bernard Ilfeld; (seated, l-r): Charles Ilfeld; Wilhelm Ilfeld; Noah Ilfeld (Las Vegas, NM; 1902-4).
  - Jaffa, Nathan and family. (Box 5)
    Family photo: Nathan; Esther; Jaffa; their children Julia; Eleanor; Ben Arthur.
    Nathan Jaffa of Roswell, New Mexico (ca. April-December 1903).
    Jaffa family photograph; standing in front, l-r: Robert Jaffa; Arthur Danziger; seated: Hedwig Jaffa Strauss; Sol Jaffa (Mrs Strauss' uncle); Esther (Essie) Strauss Jaffa; Nathan Jaffa; standing at back: Louis Rosenwald Strauss; Julia Jaffa Danziger; Ben Arthur Jaffa; Eleanor Jaffa; Joseph Danziger; Arthur Jaffa (Roswell, NM; mid-1920s).
    Nathan Jaffa on the patio at the Palace of the Governors(Santa Fe, NM; August 2-8, 1925).
    Letters from Lou R. Strauss Jr. (Nathan Jaffa's nephew) to Mr. Fierman (April 28, 1984).
  - Jewish owned stores (Albuquerque). (Box 5)
  - Laguna, New Mexico. (Box 5)
    Red safe with gold-colored trim.